SHEREEN BASSIOUNI

Interior and Graphic Designer more than 2 years of experience in the design process from the beginning of concept design to the final product. Quick learner, attentive listener, ambitious, organized, detail-oriented, strong typographic skills, understanding in colour theory and composition, team player and always open to feedback. Skilled with AutoCAD, Lumion, Blender, 3D Studio Max, Adobe CC Master Collection, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite, and web design (HTML, CSS). Able to bring liveliness and unique designs to life to meet and exceed my client's expectation.

E: shereenbassi@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/shereenbassiouni Portfolio: https://shereenbassi. myportfolio.com

EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer – The National Children's Botanical Garden of Canada

January 2021 - May 2021 | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

- Concept research; Creating mood boards with different illustration styles, colour palette and typography to be able to establish the clients chosen style
- •Designed and created illustrations using Adobe Illustrator
- Researched and gave a selection of music for the motions graphics

Design Sales Consultant - TA Blinds & Interiors Inc.

November 2020 - April 2021 | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

- Consulting and advising customers on which type of blind and drapery is best suited for them
- Selecting the fabric that would correspond with the client's needs and wants on their chosen product
- Scheduling appointments for in-store, in-home consultations and installations
- Taking payments, and invoicing

Interior & Graphic Designer - Freelance

January 2020 - Present | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

- Conceptual research: mood boards, colour palettes, furniture selection
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Drafting the floorplans, RCP, sections and elevations on Autodesk AutoCAD
- Completing FF&E and material boards
- Creating the client's branding package and establishing the brand's identity: logo design, packaging, content creation
- 3D modelling and rendering on Blender of the interior spaces

Studio Supervisor - American University in Dubai

February2019 - May 2019 | Dubai, UAE

- Teaching them how to effectively use and apply tools in Adobe Photoshop and InDesign
- Applying and researching design concepts, typography, colour theory, content layout and establishing design aesthetics
- \bullet Rendering and applying materials on floorplans, sections and 3D perspective

Interior Design Intern - Bishop Design

September 2018 - October 2018 Dubai, UAE

- Contacting, ordering and following up with suppliers for material samples for ongoing projects
- Concept research and developing; creating mood boards, furniture selection boards
- Making the material boards for different client projects that include commercial, hospitality and residential projects and organizing the material library
- Scheduling and attending meetings with new and existing suppliers
- Documenting the material and furniture specifications (FF&E)

Intern - Light Touch PLD

June 2018 - July 2018 | Dubai, UAE

- Contacting, ordering and following up with suppliers and Organizing lighting products library
- Concept research; mood boards, proposing lighting design sketches to the interior space
- Working closely with and proposing new lighting designs the Senior Designer with large clients
- Implementing, modelling and running calculations on lighting designs on Dialux Evo
- Attending meetings with new and existing suppliers Lighting specifications (FF&E)

SKILLS

- Adobe CC Master Collection
- Autodesk AutoCAD, 3D
- Studio Max
- Dialux EVO
- Blender 2.8Sketchup
- Lumion
- Microsoft Office
- HTML, CSS

- Google Drive
- Drawing
- Sculpting
- Modelling
- Photography
 - Painting
- · Graphic Design
- Branding
- GIF Animations

EDUCATION

Algonquin College

May 2021 | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada Post Graduate Certificate in Interactive Media Management

American University in Dubai

May 2019 | Dubai, UAE Bachelor of Fine Arts in Interior Design GPA 3.54, Cum Laude CIDA Accreditted.

LANGUAGES

English, Arabic, Spanish

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Esra Lemmens, Business Development - 2019

Dubai, UAE

Armstrong Ceilings, Commercial Acoustical Treatments - 2019Dubai, UAE

Herman Miller, Commerical Design - 2018

Dubai, UAE

Steelcase, Commerical Design, Offices - 2018

Dubai, UAE

Saint-Gobain Gyproc - 2018

Dubai, UAE

Reynard Lighting, Lighting Design - 2018

Dubai, UAE

Kvadrat, Acoustical Materials and Treatments - 2018

Dubai, UAE

Bishop Design LLC, Food & Beverage Design - 2018

Dubai, UAE

Shaw Contract Workshop - 2017

Dubai, UAE

Baituti Interiors, Food & Beverage Design - 2017

Dubai, UAE

MAS Paints, Paint Workshop - 2016

Dubai, UAE

Jotun, Paint Workshop - 2015

Dubai, UAE

AFFLIATIONS

Ottawa Web UX Meetup

Ottawa, Ontario

Tech+Art

Ottawa, Ontario

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Dean's List

January 2021 | Algonquin College | Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

H.H Sheikh Mohammad Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Scholarship

September 2016 - May 2019 | American University in Dubai | Dubai, UAE

Dean's List

December 2018 | American University in Dubai | Dubai, UAE Achieving a Fall 2018 semester GPA of 4.0

Dean's List

May 2018 | American University in Dubai | Dubai, UAE Achieving a Spring semester GPA of 3.82

Regional Middle East Finalist IDEC Competition

October 2018 | American University in Dubai | Dubai, UAE

Runner Up in Lighti.cation

October 2017 | Light Middle East, American University in Dubai | Dubai, UAE

INTERESTS

Travelling, culinary arts, art history, black and white photography, pottery, cultural awareness, jazz music, creative writing, poetry, vintage films, dancing, learning new languages